today we are going to talk about and
compare the most popular react.js
frameworks gatsby nextgs and the
newcomer remix these frameworks have
some things in common but also they do
things in a very different way if you
don't know which framework you should
use or if you don't understand what is
the point of a framework and why would
you need to use a framework then please
keep watching this video because those
are the questions that we're going to
answer today now before we start i think
i have to disclose something and that is
the fact that i absolutely love next.js
is my favorite framework it's not only
easy to use it's also very easy to learn
it gets better with every version that
they release and it has so many
optimizations and so many nice features
that sometimes i can't believe it's free
but anyways we're still going to be
looking at the other frameworks because
they do have valuable things to offer
that i am sure you are going to find
useful now to start let's first remember
the difference between a framework and a
library you the developer use a library
you call a library when and where you
need to
in contrast a framework calls your code
as you will see in this video when we
use any of these frameworks we are going
to have to put our code in certain
places and in certain specific files we
have to write the code in a certain way
and if we conform to the rules
everything will work well gatsby remix
and xjs they all have their differences
of course but they converge in fixing a
very common problem that many developers
have that is a problem that has to do
with client-side rendering when you make
a react application by yourself this
application will by default to be
client-side rendered which means that
only after the user goes to your website
and downloads the javascript files react
will run and react will very quickly
build the ui of your application this is
because remember react is the one
building the ui of your application so
if the user does not have javascript
enabled which to be fair is not that
common but still some people like that
exist or if the user is in a slow
connection with a slow phone and they
take a long time to download your
javascript files and the phone takes a
long time to process those javascript
files there will be a place in time
where the user is not going to see
anything from your website just a white
screen with no ui so what all these
frameworks do is to fix this problem in
one way or another of course this is not
the only problem they fixed but i chose
to show you this one because it allows
us to expose how different these
frameworks are from each other so let's
get started with gatsby but before we do
if you're enjoying this content please
consider leaving a like and subscribing
it's free for you but it helps me a lot
so here is how the most basic gatsby
project looks like
inside of the pages folder we have two
files
index.js and about js the files inside
of the pages folder will map directly to
a url so when i run the command gatsby
develop and i go to localhost in my
browser the component exported from the
index.js file will be on my homepage
since that is the index page
and the component exported from the
about js page will be on the slash about
page as you saw here we have a framework
in action gatsby is calling our code
all we have to do is put the files index
and about js in the pages folder and
that's enough for gatsby to put those
contents in the urls in our browser we
didn't do anything we didn't do the
settings we didn't make a router we
didn't do anything gatsby started and it
called our code from the pages folder
okay so to see how gatsby fixes this
client-side rendering problem let's now
run the command gatsby build after we do
this we will see that gatsby will create
a folder called public in our
application this is the folder that we
are going to upload to our server to
give to our users and it is in this
folder where we can see that gatsby has
generated two html files both for the
index and the about page if you open
these files you will see that these
files are a normal html with the code
that we wrote on the pages folder plus
some other extra code so what's going on
in here
gatsby is taking your react components
in the pages folder and is rendering
them into normal html in the public
folder this way when your users go to
your website they will see the ui of
your application immediately without
having to wait for javascript or
react.js to load while your users are
looking at the html in the background
react.js will be downloaded the code
will be executed and then when react is
ready react is going to sync with the
html and it's going to basically take
over your page to make it a fully
interactive application as you can see
this is way better than having to wait
for javascript to load so we can see
something the way gatsby does it is that
gatsby pre-generates some html page that
the user will be able to at least see
and then after the page loads everything
will be interactive the user is not
going to notice but this is not all that
gatsby does gatsby unlike next gts and
remix has something called plugins and
this is when gatsby shines plugins allow
you to add data to your application
before the pre-rendered html is
generated after creating a gatsby config
file and adding some code there i am
telling gatsby that in a new folder
called posts i am going to be writing
down markdown files for my blog because
of the plugins in my gatsby config file
when i go to my index page using graphql
i am now going to be able to extract
data from those markdown files gatsby
will run that query and give me the data
from my markdown files as the props of
my home page before the page is
generated and now all i have to do is
show the data in the page as freely as i
want and as you can see the content that
was on my markdown pages is now
automatically in the react world this is
just a taste of how gatsby plugins work
and it shows us why gatsby is such a
good choice if you are building a static
website like a landing page or a blog
using plugins you can pre-generate html
pages with data that you can bring from
anywhere you want for example a api or a
cms or the way we did it using the file
system for example you could use
wordpress to write and manage your blog
and then you can use a gatsby wordpress
plugin to bring that data from the
wordpress api and pre-generate all the
posts in your database so when the user
goes to your website the post will
already be there pre-loaded for them so
for me the verity is that if you want to
make interactive static pre-generated
websites like landing pages or blogs and
you don't mind learning a little bit of
graphql in the process then gatsby is a
very good choice now let's move on to
the new boy called remix remix is a
super new and fresh framework that is
coming from the creators of react router
remix was originally not free you had to
pay between 250 and a thousand dollars
to be able to use it but now it's free
to use when you are creating a remix
project in your console they're going to
ask you where you're going to deploy
your project in what kind of server is
your project going to live now based on
what we've seen with gatsby before you
might be wondering why do we have to
choose a server to deploy rng is we're
going to be pre-generating html files
the way gatsby does the answer is no
remix needs a server because remix runs
in server and in the browser the
client-side rendering issue that we have
been talking about is solved by remix
right from the start because
by default if you go to a website that
is using remix at every request on
demand when you go there remix is going
to render that page on the server first
which means that remix is going to run
react.js on the back end and remix is
going to take the output and give that
to the user now this means that the user
is not going to see loading indicators
anywhere when they get the page the page
will be a hundred percent fully rendered
this means they will see the ui at once
now the way we fetch data and the way we
submit data in remix is nothing like
what you have seen before inside of our
routes folder we have a page called
index remix just like gatsby will map
the names of your pages to the urls of
your website and just like gatsby the
location of these files is not optional
it has to be inside of the routes folder
in this file all we have to do is export
a react component as default and that
will be the ui that the user will see
and that will be the component that
remix is going to render in the server
side now let's add some data to our page
to do this all we have to do is export a
function named loader in this function i
am fetching data from a cryptocurrency
api called coin paprika then in the body
of our ui component all we have to do is
use the use loader data function to get
that data and be able to use it
done
that's it as you can see we're just
explaining to the framework what we
would like to happen we're just
explaining to the framework where our
data is needed and the framework is
doing the rest for us when we go to our
browser and we refresh the page we're
going to see the data there immediately
because remember remix is server side
rendered this means that in our loader
function we are able to call the
database directly that is not going to
be a security risk because again this
function runs on the server this also
means that we don't have to create api
urls or we don't have to use user state
because we know that the data is going
to be in our code when we need to so we
don't have to handle loading states as
you can see this is already very
different from gatsby because gatsby
gives you the html but it has to be
pre-rendered
generates this html on demand so we saw
how easy it is to fetch data with remix
now let's see how easy it is to submit
data with remix let's create a new file
called submit inside of the routes
folder here the user should be able to
submit the name of their new coin here
we are going to write the form code the
same way that we would do in normal html
to handle the submission of this form we
have to export a function called action
and in this function we will receive the
fields that the user wrote on the form
the action function will also run in the
server side so you'll be completely safe
to call the database from there
that is incredibly simple right simpler
than normal react we fetch data just
using the loader function and exporting
that and we just handle data using the
action function and exporting that
done the framework connects everything
for us super comfy now remix is super
new but as you can see it has a very
interesting value proposition it brings
back the comfort and the security of
doing everything in the server side and
it makes it very straightforward to
fetch data and submit data as i said
it's super new so we have to wait and
see what the community does with it and
also as i said it used to be paid and
now it's free so i will wait a little
bit longer to see what the creators are
going to do with this framework before i
jump a hundred percent but i really
really like it now it's time for next js
with gatsby we pre-generate our pages
before we publish our website and with
remix we run the code in the server side
on demand when the user wants it but in
xjs we can do both of those things next
js allows you to pre-generate pages in
your website the way gatsby would so for
example if you have a blog section in
your website you can make a blog section
with markdown files using xjs but also
next gs allows you to choose if you want
to render your pages in the server side
the way remix does or the normal react
way in the client side so you can use
the fetch and the use state and they use
effect react hooks that we are all used
to as well i couldn't possibly do
justice with the super nice features
that next gs has on this tiny video so
this is why i made a two and a half hour
free
next ggs course that you can take right
now for free with me and subtitles in
google in this course i will introduce
the framework to you and i will show you
some of the super nice features that
make nextgs the most popular react.js
framework companies like tiktok hulu
twitch binance playstation even marvel
are choosing nexus to make their
websites they have very good reasons why
and if you want to know some of these
reasons then please click the link below
and i will see you there thank you as
always for watching this video let me
know in the comments what do you think
about these frameworks have you used
them have you used gatsby have you tried
remix have you used nex js did you like
them what is your honest opinion about
them let me know in the comments thank
you as always for watching stay happy
stay free stay healthy eat kimchi
kamzamita salmon hey yo see you on the
next one
bye
[Music]